// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "For a p-type semiconductor, which of the following statements is true ?",
    answer: "Holes are the majority carriers and trivalent atoms are the dopants.",
    options: [
      "Holes are the majority carriers and trivalent atoms are the dopants.",
      "Holes are the majority carriers and pentavalent atoms are the dopants",
      "Holes are the majority carriers and pentavalent atoms are the dopants",
      "Electrons are the majority carriers and trivalent atoms are the dopants."
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "A body weighs 200 N on the surface of the earth. How much will it weigh half way down to the centre of the earth ??",
    answer: "100 N",
    options: [
      "200 N",
      "250 N",
      "100 N",
      "150 N"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "In which of the following processes, heat is neither absorbed nor released by a system?",
    answer: "Adiabatic",
    options: [
      "Adiabatic",
      "Isobaric",
      "Isochoric",
      "Isothermal"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "A force F = 20 +10 y acts on a particle in y-direction, where F is in newton and y in meter.Work done by this force to move the particle from y = 0 to y = 1m is",
    answer: "25 J",
    options: [
      "10 J",
      "25 J",
      "20 J",
      "30 J"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Two point charges A and B, having charges +Q and -Q respectively, are placed at certain distance apart and force acting between them is F. If 25% charge of A is transferred to B, then force between the charges becomes",
    answer: "9F/16",
    options: [
      "16F/9",
      "9F/16",
      "4F/3",
      "f"
    ]
  },
     {
     numb: 6,
     question: "Pick the wrong answer in the context with rainbow.",
     answer: "An observer can see a rainbow when his front is towards the sun.",
     options: [
       "The order of colours is reversed in the secondary rainbow.",
       "An observer can see a rainbow when his front is towards the sun.",
       "Rainbow is a combined effect of dispersion refraction and reflection of sunlight.",
       "When the light rays undergo two internal reflections in a water drop, a secondary rainbow is formed."
     ]
   },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Which of the following acts as a circuit protection device?",
    answer: "Fuse",
    options: [
      "Inductor",
      "Switch",
      "Fuse",
      "Conductor"
    ]
  },
  
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "A mass m is attached to a thin wire and whirled in a vertical circle.The wire is most likely to break when:",
    answer: "The mass is at the lowest point",
    options: [
      "The wire is horizontal",
      "The mass is at the lowest point",
      "The mass is at the highest point",
      "Inclined at an angle of 60° from vertical"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which colour of the light has the longest wavelength?",
    answer: "Red",
    options: [
      "Blue",
      "Green",
      "Red",
      "Violet"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Alpha-particle consists of",
    answer: "2 protons and 2 neutrons only",
    options: [
      "2 electrons, 2 protons and 2 neutrons",
      "2 electrons and 4 protons only",
      "2 protons only",
      "2 protons and 2 neutrons only"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "A copper rod of 88 cm and an aluminium rod of unknown length have their increase in length independent of increase in temperature. The length of aluminium rod is",
    answer: "68 cm",
    options: [
      "6.8 cm",
      "88 cm",
      "113.9 cm",
      "68 cm"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "In total internal reflection when the angle of incidence is equal to the critical angle for the pair of media in contact, what will be angle of refraction?",
    answer: "90 degree",
    options: [
      "0 degree",
      "Equal to angle of incidence",
      "90 degree",
      "180 degree"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "Body A of mass 4m moving with speed u collides with another body B of mass 2m, at rest. The collision is head on and elastic in nature. After the collision the fraction of energy lost by the colliding body A is",
    answer: "8/9",
    options: [
      "4/9",
      "8/9",
      "5/9",
      "1/9"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "A coil of 800 turns effective area 0.05 m2 is kept perpendicular to a magnetic field 5 10 ´ 5 - T. When the plane of the coil is rotated by 90º around any of its co-planar axis in 0.1 s, the emf induced in the coil will be",
    answer: "0.02 V",
    options: [
      "0.2 V",
      "2 V",
      "0.02 V",
      "2*10 V"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Increase in temperature of a gas filled in a container would lead to",
    answer: "Increase in its kinetic energy",
    options: [
      "Increase in its kinetic energy",
      "Decrease in its pressure",
      "Decrease in intermolecular distance",
      "Increase in its mass"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "A disc of radius 2 m and mass 100 kg rolls on a horizontal floor. Its centre of mass has speed of 20 cm/s. How much work is needed to stop it?",
    answer: "3 J",
    options: [
      "30 J",
      "2 J",
      "1 J",
      "3 J"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 17,
    question: "A hollow metal sphere of radius R is uniformly charged.The electric field due to the sphere at a distance r from the centre",
    answer: "zero as r increases for r < R, decreases as r increases for r > R",
    options: [
      "zero as r increases for r < R, decreases as r increases for r > R",
      "zero as r increases for r < R, increases as r increases for r > R",
      "Decreases as r increases for r < R and for r > R",
      "Increases as r increases for r < R and for r > R"                
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 18,
    question: "An object kept in a large room having air temperature of 25°C takes 12 minutes to cool from 80°C to 70°C.The time taken to cool for the same object from 70°C to 60°C would be nearly",
    answer: "15 min",
    options: [
      "5 min",
      "10 min",
      "15 min",
      "20 min"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 19,
    question: "The distance covered by a particle undergoing SHM in one time period is (amplitude = A)",
    answer: "4A",
    options: [
      "Zero",
      "A",
      "4A",
      "2A"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "A tuning fork with frequency 800 Hz produces resonance in a resonance column tube with upper end open and lower end closed by water surface. Successive resonance are observed at length 9.75 cm, 31.25 cm and 52.75 cm.The speed of sound in air is",
    answer: "344 m/s",
    options: [
      "500 m/s",
      "156 m/s",
      "344 m/s",
      "172 m/s"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 21,
    question: "An equi-convex lens has power P it is cut into two symmetrical halves by a plane containing the principal axis. The power of one part will be",
    answer: "P",
    options: [
      "0",
      "P/2",
      "P/4",
      "P"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 22,
    question: "The work function of a photosensitive material is 4.0 eV. This longest wavelength of light that can cause photon emission from the substance is (approximately)",
    answer: "310nm",
    options: [
      "31000nm",
      "31nm",
      "3100nm",
      "310nm"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 23,
    question: "Angular width of the central maxima in the Fraunhoffer diffraction for l = 6000 Å is q0. When thesame slit is illuminated by another monochromatic light, the angular width decreases by 30%. The wavelength of this light is",
    answer: "4200 Å",
    options: [
      "1800 Å",
      "4200 Å",
      "6000 Å",
      "420 Å"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 24,
    question: "A cycle wheel of radius 0.5 m is rotated with constant angular velocity of 10 rad/s in a region of magnetic field of 0.1 T which is perpendicular to the plane of thewheel. The EMF generated between its centre and the rim is",
    answer: "0.125 V",
    options: [
      "0.25 V",
      "0.125 V",
      "0.5 V",
      "Zero"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 25,
    question: "A circuit when connected to an AC source of 12 V gives a current of 0.2 A. The same circuit when connected to a DC source of 12 V, gives a current of 0.4 A. The circuit is",
    answer: "series LR",
    options: [
      "series LR",
      "series RC",
      "series LCR",
      "series LC"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 26,
    question: "Two toroids 1 and 2 have total number of turns 200 and 100 respectively with average radii 40 cm and 20 cm respectively. If they carry same current i, the ratio of the magnetic fields along the two loops is",
    answer: "1:1",
    options: [
      "4:1",
      "1:1",
      "2:1",
      "1:2"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 27,
    question: "A solid cylinder of mass 2 kg and radius 50 cm rolls up an inclined plane of angle inclination 30°. The centre of mass of cylinder has speed of 4 m/s. The distance travelled by the cylinder on the inclined surface will be :(Take g = 10 m/s2)",
    answer: "2.4 m",
    options: [
      "2.0 m",
      "1.6 m",
      "2.4 m",
      "2.2 m"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 28,
    question: "A double convex lens has focal length 25 cm. The radius of curvature of one of the surfaces is doubled of the other. Find the radii, if the refractive index of the material of the lens is 1.5.",
    answer: "18.75 cm, 37.5 cm",
    options: [
      "100cm, 50cm",
      "18.75 cm, 37.5 cm",
      "19 cm, 20 cm",
      "120 cm, 50 cm"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 29,
    question: "The stress-strain curves are drawn for two different materials X and Y. It is observed that the ultimate strength point and the fracture point are close to eachother for material X but are far apart for material Y. We can say that materials X and Y are likely to be (respectively)",
    answer: "Brittle and Ductile",
    options: [
      "Plastic and Ductile",
      "Ductile and Plastic",
      "Brittle and Ductile",
      "Brittle and Plastic"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 30,
    question: "An object kept in a large room having air temperature of 25°C takes 12 minutes to cool from 80°C to 70°C. The time taken to cool for the same object from 70°C to 60°C would be nearly",
    answer: "15 min",
    options: [
      "20 min",
      "12 min",
      "10 min",
      "15 min"
    ]
  },
];